这就是Barksdale案里的那个目击证人
That's the witness all right, the one from the Barksdale case.
Gant William 41岁
Gant, William. 41 years.
头部中了一枪 近距离射击
Single headshot, close range.
子弹卡在了颅内
Bullet pancaked on the inner skull.
- 也许没有你想的那么复杂 - 是么?
- Ain't necessarily what it looks like. - No?
一个人走在西Baltimore的路上
A man's walking down a street in West Baltimore.
有半打理由让你吃上一枪
That'll catch you a bullet for a half-dozen reasons.
嗯 是啊
Yeah, that it will.
查过他案底没?
You run him for a sheet?
有 只有几次妨碍治安罪
Yeah, a couple of disorderlies is all.
这家伙是Poe Homes的维修工人
Guy works maintenance down at Poe Homes.
单身 没老婆 没孩子
Lives alone, no wife, no kids.
他的名字唯一一次出现在法院的电脑里
Only time his name pops up on the courthouse computer...
就是作为Barlow案子里的公诉方证人
Is for being a state witness in Barlow's case.
否则 我根本看不会往那儿想
Otherwise, I don't even make that connection.
我是说 你得承认...
I mean, you've got to admit...
没理由在他做完证后 再做了他
It don't make sense to ace this motherfucker after he done testified.
但是给人看的意思不言而喻
Sends a hell of a message though.
他算是Terrace的一个老顽固吧
He's one hardheaded fuck in the Terrace
赶不走 也收买不了 是吧?
You can't run off or buy out, right?
如果是做给那些高层公寓里的人看
If your audience is the high-rise projects,
这个举动简直是立竿见影
A move like this cuts right through the shit.
你打算怎么对警长说
What are you gonna tell the major?
我碰上了一件难啃的迷案
That I caught a stone fucking whodunit.
- 别轻易把目击证人这茬儿放过去 - 拜托
- Don't soft-sell the witness angle. - Come on.
干嘛在我们认定之前  就先惹毛了老板?
Why get the bosses riled before we know for sure?
如果我开口就说 这个证人被杀...
If I start talking shit that a witness got killed--
- Bunk 告诉他 - 为什么?
- Bunk, tell him. - Why?
这事上罩着自己一点
Just cover yourself on this.
嘿 Jimmy
Jimmy,
你不会是想干我在想的事吧?
You ain't gonna do what I think?
听我说
Listen to me.
这事会闹起来 反咬你一口
This shit is gonna jump up and bite you in your ass.
罩着自己一点吧
Just cover yourself.
你们究竟搞什么名堂啊?
What the hell was that about?
没事
Nothing.
火线重案组 第一季 第二集 专案组
The Wire S01E02 The Detail
* When you walk through the garden *
* You gotta watch your back *
* Well I beg your pardon *
* Walk the straight and narrow track *
* If you walk with Jesus *
* He's gonna save your soul *
* You gotta keep the devil *
* Way down in the hole *
* All the angels sing *
* About Jesus' mighty sword *
* And they'll shield you with their wings *
* And keep you close to the lord *
* Don't pay heed to temptation *
* For his hands are so cold *
* You gotta help me keep the devil *
* Way down in the hole *
"不玩就不会输"  ---Marla Daniels
早上好
Morning.
我的老天爷
Jesus Christ.
该死的
Goddamn.
你得搞上谁 才能得到一间真正的办公室?
Who do you got to fuck in this town to get a real office?
起码那玩意儿还能响
At least that works.
那是找McNulty的
It was for McNulty.
- 我不该来这儿 - 那你别来啊
- I shouldn't be here. - Then you shouldn't.
可他们在法庭外面杀了你的一个证人
They killed a fucking witness out of your court.
是的 你跟我说了 你尽了你的公民责任
Yeah, you told me. You did your civic duty.
依据Baltimore市巡回法庭赋予我的权力
Under the power vested in me by the circuit court for Baltimore city...
我宽恕你所有的罪孽 McNulty探员
I absolve you of all your sins, Detective McNulty.
你才是我的罪 你知道吗?
You are my sin, you know that?
因为告诉了你 我的警长准备对我抹脖子了
For talking to you, my major is ready to cut my throat.
是啊 Jimmy 你料到我会打那通电话的 承认吧
Yeah. Jimmy, you knew I was gonna make that call. Admit it.
可我没想到你会直言不讳
I didn't think you would straight-up
把我推出去 成了众矢之的
Hang me out on the line in a shitstorm.
瞧 这跟我当检察官的时候不一样了
Look, it's not like it was when I was a prosecutor.
现在我是法官 规则变了
I'm a judge now, the rules are different.
有个地方没擦到
You missed a spot.
是的 木已成舟
Yeah, what's done is done.
问题是 现在你想让我怎么办?
Question is, what do you want me to do now?
我觉得你可以打个电话 给副局施压
I think you can leverage the Deputy Ops with a phone call.
- 他已经成立了专案组 - 什么小组啊
- He's already detailed people. - Some detail.
狗屁的副队长以为 他能通过"钓鱼"钓到Avon Barksdale
Asshole lieutenant thinks he can buy-bust his way to Avon Barksdale.
你想要施压?
You want leverage?
我们可以把证人被杀告诉报纸
We give the dead-witness angle to the newspapers.
搅个天翻地覆
Stir some real shit.
不 那就等于给Barksdale暗示 有人在查他
No, that tips Barksdale that someone's working him.
- 我们不想公开 - 是么?
- We don't want to go public. - No?
只要告诉副局...
Just put it to the Deputy Ops...
一个在你庭上作证的人死了
You lost a witness who testified in your court.
逼着当局去承诺彻查
That forces the department to commit to the investigation.
这次你再给Burrell打电话 能不能拜托别提我这该死的名字?
And when you call Burrell this time, will you forget my fucking name?
嘿 你漏了一个地方
Hey. You missed a spot.
它妈的你怎么不拖?
Why don't you fucking do it?
辈分摆在这儿
Seniority.
你找到我们了
You found us.
不容易啊
Wasn't easy.
你要来的人?
You asked for these guys?
我要的是多点人手
I asked for more manpower.
坐
Have a seat.
搞什么飞机...
What the fuck....
长官 我...
Sir, l--
他在给我看他Glock(自动手枪)的扳机
He was showing me the trigger pull on his Glock.
他就这么...
And he was just--
探员?
Detective?
Pryzbylewski警员开枪打中了墙壁 副队
Officer Pryzbylewski shot the wall, Lieutenant.
为什么?
Why?
你干嘛冲墙开枪 Pryzbylewski警员?
Why did you shoot the wall, Officer Pryzbylewski?
我只是想给Carv看看我的扳扣有多轻巧
I was just showing Carv how my trigger pull is light, you know.
所以证明真的很轻巧
I got it so it's real light.
他卸下弹夹的 老板
He took the clip out, boss.
但不是枪膛里的那条
But not the one in the chamber.
不 我忘记了在枪膛里的
No, I forgot the one in the chamber,
而且...
And....
该死的 对不起 副队
Shit, I'm sorry, lieutenant.
你想让他打报告吗?
You want him to write on it?
打什么报告?
Write on what?
你开了一枪 就得打报告
You let one go, you got to write.
为你使用致命武器正名
You got to justify the use of deadly force.
朝一堵石灰墙而已
Against a plaster wall.
不过是个意外 好吧 它妈的让我喘口气吧
It's an accident, okay? Give me a fucking break already.
你叫什么?
Your name is what?
Pryzbylewski
Pryzbylewski.
从车管队(专门调查汽车犯罪)那调来的 对吧?
From Auto Unit, right?
Cantrell调派的你
Cantrell sent you.
不全对
Not exactly.
Cantrell副队 他...
Lt. Cantrell
几个月前 他调我去了事故科
He sent me to Casualty Section a couple months back.
我请求离开那里
And I asked out of Casualty.
你是从事故科转过来的?
You came here from Casualty Section?
哥们 这东西超正点
Man, these shits is right, yo.
蘸点辣酱也很好吃
It's good with the hot sauce, too.
当然
Most definite.
Dee 要来点麦乐鸡吗?
Dee, want some nuggets?
不了 你们吃吧
No, go ahead, man.
伙计 谁发明了这玩意 谁就发了
Man, whoever invented these, he off the hook.
说得好!
Word!
狗娘养的居然把鸡里的骨头全抽了出来
Motherfucker got the bone all the way out the damn chicken.
在他之前 大家还在啃鸡腿...
Till he came along, niggas be chewing on drumsticks and shit...
把手指弄得油腻腻的
Getting their fingers all greasy.
他对骨头说"别了"
He said "Later" to the bone.
做出了麦乐鸡 挣到了大钱
Nugget that meat up and make some real money.
你觉得那人有钱拿?
You think the man got paid?
谁?
Who?
那个发明这些小吃的
Man who invented these.
操 他娘的比谁都有钱
Shit, he richer than a motherfucker.
为什么? 你觉得他拿到了分成?
Why? You think he get a percentage?
为什么没呢?
Why not?
哥们 拜托 发明了这些东西的人
Nigga, please, the man who invented them things...
不过是在麦当劳的地下室里窝着的倒霉蛋
Just some sad-ass down at the basement of McDonald's...
想着搞出新点子 卖给真正的主来捞钱
Thinking up some shit to make money for the real players.
- 不 伙计 不对 - 妈的有什么不对
- No man, that ain't right. - Fuck right.
管它对不对 要紧的是钱
It ain't about right, it's about money.
你觉得Ronald McDonald会跑到地下室说
You think Ronald McDonald gonna go down that basement and say,
"鸡块先生 你真牛叉"
"Mr. Nugget, you the bomb.
"我们卖鸡的速度比你剔骨的速度还快"
"We selling chicken faster than you can tear the bone out.
"所以 我要在这张给你的大支票上签上我滑稽的名字"
"So, I'm gonna write my clowny-ass name on this fat-ass check for you."
妈的
Shit.
发明了它们的家伙...
The nigger who invented them things...
仍旧在地下室里 为了份普通的工资卖命...
Still working in the basement for regular wage...
琢磨着有什么法子 能让薯条吃上去更脆之类的...
Thinking of some shit to make the fries taste better some shit like that.
相信吧
Believe.
但点子还是他想的
He still had the idea, though.
谁
Who?
Polk和Pat Mahone
Polk and Pat Mahone.
- 两个物管科(管理扣押的物品)来的家伙 - 我不认识他们
- A couple of drunks from Property. - I don't know them.
你们怎么会认识 他们10年没办过案子了
Why would you? They haven't made a case in 10 years.
还有个小毛孩 叫Prezbelowski 或者是Prezbelewski...
Also got handed some kid named Prezbelowski or Prezbelewski--
Pryzbylewski 我知道他
Pryzbylewski, him, I know.
是吗? 他怎么去的事故科?
Yeah? Why was he in Casualty Section?
他打中了自己的车 记得吗?
He shot up his own car. You remember?
他干了什么?
He did what?
他朝一辆没有标志的车开了两梭
He fired two clips into an unmarked car,
就在Baltimore西区某个地方
Somewhere out in West Baltimore.
还向电台请求支援 搞得像是受到了狙击 (讯号13:请求支援)
Called in a Signal 13 on the radio, like he was under fire from a sniper.
你居然没听说过?
You didn't hear about that?
他坚称了半天
He stuck to his story for half a day,
直到弹道科发现 子弹来自他的非当班手枪
Until Ballistics matched the bullet to his off-duty weapon.
我们差点以报假案起诉他
We almost indicted him for false report.
为什么没呢?
Why didn't you?
他和市长办公室有点瓜葛 我说不准
He's got some kind of suction with the Mayor's office. I'm no exactly.
我要说的是 靠这些派给我的废物 我可做不出什么成绩
My point is, I can't build much with the garbage they sent me.
那就去找副局啊 这案子不是他在抓吗?
So, go to the deputy, right? You've got his ear on this.
为什么不去?
Why not?
我向副局要过人手
I ask the deputy for manpower.
然后他让物管科派了两个人来
He then tells Property to send me two men,
另外让特勤科派两个
And Special to send two more.
那些轮班副队...
And those shift lieutenants...
他们知道这是个废物处理的机会
They know it's a chance to dump their deadwood.
而副局 他也知道
The deputy, he knows this, too.
他本可以提出由我挑选 却没有
He could have offered to let me pick but he didn't.
- 算是他给我的暗示吧 - 什么暗示
- He sent me a message on this. - And the message is?
别深入 别搞大
Don't dig in, don't get fancy.
快点给这个Barksdale按个罪名然后结案
Put a quick charge on this Barksdale and then get out.
如果他能给我派些好警察 我自然能好好查
If he sends me good police, I might do good police work.
- 不过如果检察院这里.. - 不 不
- But if the state's attorney's office were to-- - No, no.
Rhonda 亲爱的..
Rhonda, darling...
如果我无视已经得到的帮助 再要求支援就不合情理了
It's bad protocol for me to ask for help and then trash the help I'm given.
- 而你 反过来说... - 没门
- You, on the other hand-- - No way.
我的办公室可不做这种事
My office doesn't play that way.
你们招兵买马查案子 再移交给我们
You people staff your cases, you bring us casework.
我插手 只能把大家都惹毛了
I cross that line, I only piss everyone off.
最多我告诉我的老板 你办案不利
Best I can do is tell my unit chief that you drew shit.
如果他想捅到上面 让人报告给副局 那也得看他的决定了
He wants to take it upstairs and someone call the deputy for operations, that's his choice.
- 不会的 - 很可能不会
- That won't happen. - Probably not.
凑合凑合吧
Make lemonade.
操!
Fuck!
嘿 Kima 你要带我们去哪儿?
Yo, Kima, where you taking us?
- 蹲下 - 什么?
- Get down. - What?
天 你们就不会弯个腰吗
Jesus. You all ain't got no creep to you.
两头该死的大象
Pair of goddamn elephants.
刚有颗生锈的钉子戳穿了我的鞋子
A rusted nail just went through my shoe.
我得去打支破伤风 免得感染了
I'm gonna need a tetanus to get behind this bullshit.
Kima
Kima.
把包递给我
Hand me that bag.
Kima 如果你不介意我多嘴
Kima, if you don't mind me asking...
你什么时候发现你喜欢女人多过男人的?(Kima为拉拉)
When was it that you first figured you liked women better than men?
我介意
I mind you asking.
伙计们 你们好吗 哥们?
Gentlemen, what's going on there, guys?
伙计 货卖完了
Testers, man, already out.
不 我不需要劳驾你们 哥们
No. I'm not in need of your services, bro.
我是来为你们效劳的
I'm offering my services to y'all.
你包里有什么 伙计?
What you got in the bag, man?
比一双时髦的鞋子更受黑兄弟欢迎的
One thing a gentleman of color like better than a new pair of downtown shoes...
是一顶时髦的宽沿帽 不是吗?
Is a downtown brim, right?
那帽子有什么蹊跷么
What's with the hats?
50!(警察)
Five-o!
50!
收摊!
Shut it down!
- 50! - 收摊!
- Five-o! - Shut it down!
安全?
Clean?
嘿 别想把这东西栽在我头上
You ain't gonna put that one on me.
他是目击证人
He a witness.
这是你从地上捡的  别想栽赃在我身上
You picked that shit up off the ground, so don't be trying to put shit on me.
你以为这是我的打算?
Is that what you think I'm about?
这伙计觉得我会黑他
Boy thinks I'm gonna dirty him.
别说的你们不会似的
Like y'all won't do it.
你们这些西区的缉毒警 一来这儿就会从地上捡个破烂
You Western knockos come here, picking shit up off the ground...
随便栽在哪个想整的人身上
Putting it on whoever you damn well please.
我认识你吗?
Do I know you?
让我们互相理解一下
Let's understand each other.
我不是西区的
I'm not Western District.
我也不是缉毒警
I'm not a knocko.
我不嫁祸谁 因为我不在乎告谁非法藏毒
I don't dirty people because I don't care about a possession charge.
我是干缉凶的 我来这是为了具尸体
I'm a Murder Police, I'm here about the bodies.
这里的D'Angelo清楚这事
D'Angelo here knows that.
他记得我去过他的庭审 对吧?
He remembers me from the trial, right?
我就坐在后排 Stringer后面
I'm sitting in back there, behind Stringer,
看着 听着
Watching, listening.
你们是为那破事找上我?
Y'all hassling me about that shit?
我以为你听到陪审团说的了
I thought you heard what the jury had to say.
去它妈的陪审团
Fuck the jury.
是啊 去它妈的陪审团 我们聊聊而已 不是吗?
Yeah, fuck the jury. This is just us talking, right?
就你 我 我的搭档 还有...
Just you, me, my partner and....
你说你叫什么?
What did you say your name was?
我有放屁吗?
I didn't say shit.
就你 我 我的搭档 还有放屁先生
Just you, me, my partner and Mr. Shit here.
我们不过是在聊聊近况 不是吗?
We're just talking about how things go, right?
交流下想法
We are just sharing our thoughts here.
Bunk 一个给你装想法的小瓶
Bunk, a vial for your thoughts.
我想 你们在Terrace的小伙计
I'm thinking it's one thing for one of you Iittle Terrace niggers
在221大楼的大堂里开枪打死人是一回事
To shoot somebody in the lobby of the 221 building, you know?
- 谁在乎? - 没错 但是当你们干掉一个目击证人
- Who gives a fuck? - right. But when you ace a witness...
- 一个工人 - ...他根本是个局外人
- A working man. - ... who ain't even in the game.
你打算装作才听说?
You gonna act like this is news?
告诉你们 我丫什么都不知道
I tell you this, I don't know shit about shit,
但是我知道这个
But I do know this.
谁无聊到有空作证
Anyone who spend time witnessing shit,
有报应是活该
You gonna get got.
我知道听起来不太顺耳
I know that sounds kind of harsh,
但是在这里就是这样...警官
But that's the way things go around here... officer.
走咯!
Let's roll.
你也这么看吗 D'Angelo?
That how you see things, D'Angelo?
跟你朋友一样的想法?
Like your friend here?
我要在这儿帮哥们打扮打扮 用能让娘们发骚的东西
I'm here trying to outfit niggers with something to rile up some pussy.
你们别不想听 我以前可会钓马子了
You don't want to know, Bubbles used to get that pussy.
我觉得如果不戴上一顶宽沿帽
I reckon the pussy ain't worth what it used to be...
就能泡上的娘们 也许就不值得你费心思了...
If you can do it without a proper brim, right?
来啊 大块头
Come on, big man.
不对劲
Something's up.
什么?
What?
不知道
Don't know.
嘿 Carv
Yo, Carv.
过来
Come here.
听着 你看到Bubbs只要给人戴上帽子
Listen, you see Bubbs put a hat on anybody...
你就拍下来 好吗
You take some pictures, all right?
- 啊? - 特别是红帽子
- Yeah? - Especially the red one.
如果你看到他把红帽子给谁戴上
If you see him put that red hat on anybody's head...
就给我不停地按快门
Snap your fucking fingers off.
你去哪儿?
Where you going?
嘿 Carv
Yo, Carv.
注意到没 很多时候Kima像是在管着我们?
Notice that most of the time it's like Kima thinks she's above us or something?
我是说 我可没在她袖子上看到什么杠杠...
I mean, I don't see any stripes on her fucking sleeve...
我可没看到
I don't see that.
我就看到一个尾巴翘到天上去的死拉拉...
All I see is some stuck-up dyke bitch...
来刑侦处的时间连我们的一半都不及...
Who ain't been in CID half the time of you or me...
它妈的居然敢指挥我们
And she's fucking telling us what to do.
怎么能这样
It ain't right.
你觉得能这样?
You think it's right?
你瞧 伙计 就闭上会儿嘴吧 我正击中精力搞这玩意儿
Yo,man. Shut up for just a minute. I'm trying to concentrate on this shit here.
车子挺拉风
Nice truck.
不要?
No?
让你的口气清新自然
Makes your breath minty fresh.
你们不是来抓我的吗? 那就它妈的放手来抓呀
Is you all gonna arrest me? Then go the fuck ahead and arrest me.
如果不是 丫的闭嘴
If not, shut the fuck up.
- 你想被抓? - 没
- You want to get arrested? - No.
- 那你丫自己闭嘴吧 - 操 我走了
- Shut the fuck up your own self. - Fuck yo, I'm out of here.
嘿 嘿 D'Angelo
Hey, D'Angelo.
你最好乖乖地趴回来
You better bend the fuck over.
操
Shit.
你们今天没别的事做了?
You ain't got nothing else to do today?
没 没 没事了
No, no, nothing.
你们没什么罪名安给我
Y'all ain't got no charge.
你摸得太深了 伙计 你新入行的吗?
You're getting awfully close, man. You new on the force or some shit?
好了 Dee
All right, Dee.
快走
Move it.
我是Greggs 给我接副队
It's Greggs. Get me the lieutenant.
Prez? 在谁手下都没用 他是个废人
Prez? He's no good to anyone, he's a goof.
怎么让他成了我的麻烦?
How is he my problem then?
怎么还给他枪和警徽
How is he still carrying a gun and badge?
你知道东南片的Valchek吗?
You know Valchek in Southeast?
是的
Yeah.
他女婿
Son-in-law.
我没法带他办这案子
I can't carry him on this.
- 你知道特勤科给我派了谁 - 谁?
- You know who Special sent me? - Who?
Polk和Mahoney
Polk and Mahoney.
两个人里面 我连个可靠的司机都找不到(两人都是酒鬼)
Between the two of them I don't have a designated driver.
我听说有个从缉脏科(专门从典当行追踪赃物)那调来的
I heard you have someone from Pawnshop.
Lester Freamon? 一只温驯的家猫
Lester Freamon? A cuddly housecat.
我觉得他连自己的枪都找不到
I don't think he can even find his gun.
瞧 把Pryzbylewski收回去吧
Look, take Pryzbylewski back.
你瞧我办不到  我愿意 但是我不能
You know I can't. I would, but I can't.
我已经答应Valchek了 好吧
I gave Valchek my word on it, okay?
我又没法阻止Prez搞那家伙的女儿
I can't help it that Prez is fucking the guy's daughter.
要不是那样 他早滚了 没得说
If not for that, he's gone, no question.
那你跟Valchek搭上了?
So, you got suction with Valchek?
如果我跟他唱反调 下一轮升迁就没我的戏了
If I cross him, I'm fucked on the next round of promotions.
看在上帝的份上  我和你都在警长的候选名单上
For Christ's sake, I'm with you on the short list for major.
Valchek在一区民主俱乐部活跃
Valchek has suction with the First District Democratic Club...
而他们和市长有往来
And they got suction with the Mayor,
我就是个受压迫的小人物
And I'm the runt without a tit here.
我欠你个人情 好吧
I owe you, okay?
那就把Sydnor调给我
So, give me Sydnor.
没门
No way.
给我Sydnor 我就留下Prez
Give me Sydnor and I'll keep Prez.
他是我最得利的手下 你不能要走他
He's my best man, you can't take him.
我留下了你最烂的一个 记得吗?
I'm taking your worst, remember?
Steinman如何?
How about Steinman?
我查的是Baltimore西区的毒品案
I'm working drugs in West Baltimore,
我需要一个黑人盯梢 我需要Sydnor
I need a black guy for surveillance. I need Sydnor.
老天爷 你知道Prez今天早上干了什么吗?
Jesus, know what Prez did this morning?
说来听听
Tell me.
他开枪打了一堵墙  就在专案组的办公室打空弹
He put a bullet through a wall, dry-firing in the detail office.
瞧 我不给保证
Look, no promises.
不过你给我Sydnor  我就尽量帮你兜着Pryzbylewski
You give me Sydnor, I'll carry Pryzbylewski as long as I can.
好吧 Cedric 操 随便了 老天爷
Fine, Cedric, fuck, whatever. Jesus Christ.
你怎么应付法官的
How did you handle the judge?
我告诉他 我们正查得紧
I told him we were looking closely at the situation.
请他先不要告诉外面
I asked him not to say anything publicly.
那么 他不会公之于众 对吧?
So, then he's not gonna go public, right?
Phelan法官今早打来电话...
Judge Phelan called this morning...
大叫出庭的证人被杀了
Crying about a witness in his murder trial who was killed.
法官有说从哪儿听说的吗?
Did the judge say where he heard it?
从我们的人那听到的 McNulty
He heard it from our man, McNulty.
简直成了他的顺风耳
That's his pipeline on this crap.
抱歉我的口不择言  不过这种时候我一点都不介意那混蛋滚蛋
Pardon my French, but I got no problem giving that asshole up at this point.
我不需要不能让我信任的家伙
I don't need people I can't trust.
谁会想要
Yeah, who does?
要是让报纸听到了这风声 还不炒个天翻地覆
The newspapers get hold of this, it'll be a complete clusterfuck.
好吧 现在要做的事情 是让法官恢复信心...
Okay, so the thing to do is reassure the judge...
让他别站上该死的发言台
Keep him off his damn soapbox.
一两次抓捕行动会有帮助
An arrest or two would help.
如果是真的呢?
What if it's true?
如果的确是Barksdale下令 暗杀公诉方的证人呢?
What if Barksdale ordered the murder of a state's witness?
你不是开玩笑吧?
Are you serious?
谁会在证人做完证后再干这种事?
Why would anyone do that after the witness testifies?
对案子已经没影响了
It has no effect on the case.
报复 直截了当
Payback, plain and simple.
胡扯 什么直截了当
Bullshit, plain and simple.
瞧
Look,
我知道还有十足的理由解释这男人遇害
I know there could be two dozen other reasons for this man to be murdered,
- 但要是... - 没钱搞预审
- but what if-- - No money for pretrial.
没有证人保护计划
No witness protection program.
瞧 这是座一穷二白的城市 先生们
Look, this is a poor fucking city, gentlemen.
我们最不想做的
The last thing we ever need to do is
就是宣布我们失去了一位证人
To announce we lost a witness.
我是说 原本要把重案
I mean, it's hard enough pushing felony casework
搞上法庭就不是一件容易的事
Through that courthouse as it is.
你得把McNulty换下来
You got to pull McNulty off this.
那谁来查凶杀案呢?
Who caught the murder case?
Bunk Moreland...McNulty的搭档
Bunk Moreland, McNulty's partner.
那你也得把他调开
Then you'd have to pull him, too.
不 如果我们换下McNulty
No, we pull McNulty up,
那法官肯定会让媒体搅和进来
The judge will bring the press into this.
我看那情形也不远了
I can see that a mile away.
不 我们得淡定点
No, we're gonna sit tight,
让McNulty自己发挥去
Let McNulty take his best shot...
死命祈祷他功亏一篑
And hope like hell he comes up short.
你想怎么处理?
How do you wanna handle this?
我们手上没他的证据
We got nothing on him.
如果我们正面交锋 他会马上看穿我们
We try to front, he'll see right through us.
- 不过他害怕了 - 蔫了
-He's scared though. -Soft.
- 进去唱双簧? - 嗯
- Go with the deuce? - mm-uhm.
等等 等等
Hold up, hold up.
他牵涉我的案子了?
He part of my case?
不 长官
No, sir.
他是我谋杀案里的嫌疑人
He's a potential suspect in my murder.
也许也涉了我的案
Which might be part of my case.
我想喝点咖啡 你想来点吗?
I could use some coffee. You want some coffee?
我要跟你说几句
I need a word with you.
- 副队 我们正要进去... - 现在
- Lieutenant, we're just about to go-- - Now.
你还记得我对你说的 随时跟我汇报
You remember all that bullshit I gave you about keeping me informed...
让我了解案情进展的每一步吗?
About nothing happening that I don't know about?
- 副队 - 那不是在放屁
- Lieutenant-- - Wasn't bullshit.
我的搭档发现了一件凶杀案
My partner caught a murder.
也许跟Barksdale毫无瓜葛
It may have nothing with Barksdale at all.
我刚从副局的办公室来...
I just came from Deputy Ops' office
在那里 你自己的警长告诉Burrell 要收拾了你
Where your own major's telling Burrell to do you.
你听到了吗? Rawls要让你滚蛋
You hear me? Rawls is giving you up.
它妈的我干什么了
What the fuck did I do?
你闭不上你的嘴
You can't shut your mouth.
你以为那个城里的法官会在这事上保你?
You think that downtown judge is gonna bail your ass out on this?
你真的那么想?
You really think that?
你应该来找我
You should have come to me.
如果我们把这事先通报副局 那我们还有余地
We bring this business to the deputy first, we got a shot.
不过没有 你一个人在外面上蹿下跳
But no, you're out there all alone, jumping bad.
- 你能让副局听你的? - 这案子上 我能
- You got the deputy's ear? - On this case, I do.
那怎么会派一群没用的文职来?
Then how come they sent every worthless hump in plainclothes?
你是要人手 结果他们派来了酒鬼和蠢货
You ask for men, they send you drunks and fuck-ups.
我想破这案子
I want to do this case.
我也是
So do l.
那你就得全心全意地投入了 副队
Then you're gonna get all the way in, Lieutenant.
只有这样 我才能了解你 明白你想干什么
If I see you get all the way in, then I know who you are, what you're about.
他是谁?
Who is he?
D'Angelo Barksdale 国王的外甥
D'Angelo Barksdale. Nephew to the king.
就是那个翻案的家伙?
That's the one that beat the murder?
是的 就是他
Yeah, him.
你有什么能把他和被害的证人联系起来?
What do you have to connect him to the dead witness?
什么都没有
Not a thing.
那你抓他进来干什么?
Why did you pick him up?
给他施压 看他能有什么松动
Press him. See what kind of flex he shows.
她跟你进去
She goes in with you.
我们不需要她
We don't need her.
Bunk和我 我们有自己的节奏
Bunk and me, we got our own rhythm.
你想算上我一个吗 McNulty?
You want me in, McNulty?
我以为你想算上我
I thought you said you wanted me in.
审讯你进去旁听 但这算凶案科的案子 就让他主审好了
You're along for this interview, but it's Homicide's play, so let him lead.
你也许可以去查一下这两辆车的记录
You might want to run tag and title on these two trucks.
我们带走孩子的时候  他们进入了我们的视野
They scoped us when we jacked the kid.
我也在
Been there.
资料已经在案卷里了
Info's already in the file.
今天你们不是唯一在Canyon的公差
Y'all weren't the only lawmen down in the Canyon today.
真的 你在哪儿?
Really, where were you?
她在哪儿?
Where was she?
我是说 我不知道为什么这男人会死
I mean, the thing is, I can't see a reason for that man to be dead.
我想不出来
I can't.
我是说 没错 你在法庭上赢了我们
I mean, hell, you beat us in court.
我们不会公报私仇
We don't take it personal.
- 妈的 不会 - 反正我们薪水照拿
- Fuck, no. - We get paid either way.
又不是你真的干了罪恶滔天的事
And it's not like you did anything real bad
不过是对着Pooh Blanchard开了两枪
Throwing a couple of hot ones at Pooh Blanchard.
没人会怀念那个混蛋 对吧
No one's gonna miss that motherfucker.
但是你知道这次被杀的人吗?
But you know the man who got killed this time?
你知道这个可怜蛋是谁吗?
You know who that poor son of a bitch was?
一个老百姓
A citizen.
每天都辛苦工作
Worked every goddamn day of his life.
你知道吗?
You know that?
他每天都会起来 出去搞维修
He would get up every day, go out and do maintenance work.
到了周末 他会开着的士去机场
Then on the weekends, he was driving a cab out to the airport.
两份工
Two jobs.
他还会花上点业余时间在教堂里当义工
And he volunteers what little time he has left at his church.
虔诚的教徒
Church-going man.
一个圣徒 一个执事
A bethel man, a deacon.
两份工作 三个孩子
Two jobs and three kids.
你知道吗?
Did you know that?
三个孩子 也都还小
Three kids. Young, too.
5岁 8岁 11岁
Five, eight, eleven.
无父无母 哭着睡着
Crying their little orphaned asses to sleep over the little shit
因为几年前他们失去了自己的妈妈
'cause they lost their mama some years ago
现在他们只能靠自己了
And now they out there on their own.
他不信我们
He doesn't believe us.
我知道他不会信
I know he don't believe it.
我们在这呆了两个小时 告诉你真实世界里发生的事
We've been here two hours, telling you what's true in the world
而你坐在那里 像个没事儿人似的
And you sit like nothing happened.
我的律师在哪儿
Where my lawyer at?
我们给过他电话了 到了会通知你
We called him. When he comes, we'll let you know.
我没什么可说的
I got nothing to say.
我是说 我为那男人感到遗憾 但是我没什么可说的
I mean, I'm sorry for the man, but I ain't got nothing to say.
你感到遗憾?
You sorry?
你为他遗憾? 你它妈的杀了他
You sorry for him? You fucking killed the man.
- 没有 - 是的 你有
- No. - Yes, you did.
我是说 我们不认为你开枪杀了他
We don't think that you shot him or anything
要是你没有忙着在大楼的大堂里开枪杀人
But if you weren't so busy Iighting folks up in high-rise lobby
他也不会一出电梯就目击到整件事
He ain't coming out of the elevator and see it happen.
他没看到 也就不会作证
He don't see anything, he doesn't testify.
他不作证 那些孩子就还有个老爹可以依靠
He doesn't testify, those kids still got a daddy to lean on.
- 他干嘛要作证呢? - 我们他妈的怎么知道
- Why'd he testify? - How would we know?
他没必要作证
He didn't have to testify.
是的 没必要 但是他做了
No, he didn't, but he did.
而你仍旧翻案了 不是吗?
And you still beat the charge, didn't you?
但是那还不够 对吧 打赢了谋杀官司还不够
But that wasn't enough. It's not enough to beat the murder.
他们得给所有在Terrace的人放话
They gotta send a cold message to everyone in the Terrace.
操他妈的维修工人
Fuck the working man.
操他妈的小屁孩 算个鸟啊
Fuck his kids, that shit don't count.
瞧 这就是我看不透贩毒的地方
See, that's what I don't get about the drug thing.
你们干嘛不能卖完之后 拍拍屁股走人呢?
Why can't you sell the shit and walk the fuck away?
懂我的意思吗?
You know what I mean?
其他买卖里 成交之后没有再交火的
Everything else in this country gets sold without people shooting each other behind it.
而在Terrace 尸体是一具接着一具
In the Terrace, it's one body after another.
你还记得那个小男孩吗
You remember that little boy...
去年夏天在西Lombard街的理发店里被枪杀
Got shot in the barbershop on West Lombard last summer?
只因为一个混蛋追着别人来到那里
One asshole chases another into a house nature
把一把手枪都打空了
Empties a 9.
只为了争20粒不见的胶囊
Bullshit argument over 20 missing gelcaps.
而那个小孩子 没有得到人生中第一次理发 反而一只眼睛吃到了子弹
And that little kid, instead of getting his first haircut he gets one in the eye.
你还记得吗?
You remember that?
真操蛋
It's fucked up.
是的 的确
Yes, it is.
他们不必那么做
They didn't have to do that.
在理发店里开枪?
Shoot up a barber shop?
不 他们不必那么做
No, they did not have to do that.
那个男的...
That man was just...
是我的事
My thing.
我的事 他们不必...
My thing, they ain't had....
他们不必那么做
They ain't had to do that.
没有妈妈 没有爸爸
No mama and no daddy.
老天爷啊
Lord Jesus!
我告诉你我觉得你该做什么 D'Angelo
I'll tell you what I think you should do, D'Angelo.
不是因为我觉得你想杀了那男人..
Not because I think you wanted that man to get shot...
还是跟枪杀他有任何瓜葛
Or had anything to do with shooting him.
而是我觉得你可以坐在这里...
But I think you could just sit here...
坐上一会儿 理理自己的思路
For a moment or two, collect your thoughts,
好好想清楚
You know, get your shit together.
然后我觉得也许你可以
And then I think it might be a good thing
给那些孩子写几句话也挺不错的
For you to write a little letter to those children
让他们知道你很遗憾...
And you let them know you're sorry...
对于他们失去了所有亲人这件事
That they're not gonna have anyone left, you know?
我是说 随便说什么
I mean, just say something.
告诉他们你个人认为你的舅舅
Tell them how you personally think your uncle...
也许这次错了 因为的确是错了...
Maybe he got it wrong this time, because it's wrong...
事情结束了 他们却失去了他们的老爹
That they lost their daddy behind what happened, you know?
让他们知道你对他们是同情的 也许对他们来说有点意义
It might mean something to them to know that you're feeling for them.
伙计 我没什么好说的
Man, I ain't got nothing to say.
就说你的心里话
Just say what's in your heart.
教堂的执事? 真能扯
Church deacon? That was thick.
我觉得不错 能说什么呢?
Got good to me, what can I say?
把孩子说成孤儿就够可怜的了
It's sad enough with the kids being orphaned and everything.
照片是Bunk桌上的
Photo was from Bunk's desk.
他们是你的孩子?
They're yours?
嗯 恐怕是的
Yeah, afraid so.
真走运他们长得像妈妈
Good thing they look like their mama.
Maurice Levy刚才现身了
Maurice Levy just posted.
就在电梯里
He's by the elevators.
- 辩护律师从不休息 - 鄙视你 McNulty
- The defense never rests. - Shame on you, McNulty.
把我从周五Levy家族的聚会上拖出来
Dragging me from the Levy family preserve on a Friday night.
- 向你道歉 - Yvette烹调了牛胸肉
- My apologies. - Yvette made brisket.
- 好吃吗? - 热气腾腾 1号室还是2号室?
- Good? - When served hot. One or two?
委托人是你的了
Your client.
搞什么飞机! 别写了! 马上!
What the fuck! Stop writing! Now!
- 我只是在... - 闭嘴!
- I'm just-- - Shut up!
他打电话叫了律师 那就意味着审讯结束
He calls his lawyer, that's supposed to be the end of the interview.
你的委托人没有口供 我们也没有收到口供
Your client gave no statement, we took no statement.
他不过是决定 自愿给受害者的家庭写一封信
He just decided, voluntarily, to write a letter to the victim's family.
- 写下... - 闭嘴!
- To say that-- - Shut up!
有什么指控吗?
Any charge here?
- 没有指控 - 好 起来
- No charge. - Good, get up.
走! 闪人!
Go! Walk!
听我说 你什么都不要说 什么都不要做
Listen to me, you don't say anything, you don't do anything,
什么都不要写 你听见了吗?
You don't write anything. Do you hear me?
闭嘴!
Shut up!
我对你们这些人它妈的重复过多少遍了?
How many times do I have to tell you people the same fucking thing?
它妈的是什么玩意儿?
What the fuck is that?
雕饰衣柜
Armoire.
路易十四风格
Louis Quatorze.
我是说 那是什么 玩具吗?
I mean, what is it, a toy?
你们中有些我认识
Some of you I know.
有些我很快会认识
Some of you I will know.
如果你们曾和我共事过 你们就知道我不要什么独行侠
If you've ever worked with me before, you know I don't want cowboy shit...
我不要惊喜
And I don't want surprises.
目标就是...
The task...
Avon Barksdale
is Avon Barksdale,
也只有Avon Barksdale
And Avon Barksdale only.
不要招三惹四 横生枝节
No sidetrips, no sprawl.
主干是我组里的Greggs
Primary investigators are Greggs from my unit
和...
And--
我组里的Greggs和凶案科的McNulty
Greggs from my unit and McNulty from Homicide.
他们负责汇报
They keep the file.
在街上 我们两两搭档
On the street, we work partners.
Greggs和Sydnor一组 Herc和Carver一组
Greggs and Sydnor. Herc and Carver.
McNulty和Santangelo一组 Mahone和Polk一组
McNulty's with Santangelo, Mahone and Polk.
Pryzbylewski和Freamon一组
Pryzbylewski and Freamon.
- 首先 我们有9... - 那个怎么样?
- To start with, we got nine-- - How's that?
行了吗?
Did that get it?
什么?
What?
你能听见我吗?
Do you hear me?
什么?
What?
首先 我们有9或10宗凶杀案
To start with, we have nine or ten open homicide files..
需要回顾找头绪
To work back through for leads.
McNulty和Santangelo 他们已经在查了
McNulty and Santangelo, they're on that already.
Herc...Carver...Sydnor和我
Herc, Carver, Sydnor, and me,
我们会针对街上的毒贩...
We'll be targeting street dealers...
从他们那追查出Barksdale的手下
And rolling them back up at Barksdale's people.
Polk和Mahone可以去查一些特殊的线索
Polk and Mahone are available to run down specific leads.
Freamon和Pryzbylewski先在办公室里做文案
Freamon, Pryzbylewski, are gonna start in-office on clerical duty.
如果你们需要检察官...
You need a prosecutor--
不 把那狗娘养的关掉!
No, turn the shit off!
什么!
What?
你们需要一个检察官
You need a prosecutor.
缉毒科的Rhonda Pearlman已经派过来了
Rhonda Pearlman from Narcotics is assigned.
现在既然我们还没有足够的桌椅 所以我们得合用一下...
Now, we don't have enough desks yet, so we gotta share--
你们都是来自采购科的?
Y'all from Purchasing?
不是
No.
就像我说的
Like I was saying,
上头答应给我们电脑和监视设备
We've been promised some computers and surveillance equipment.
问题?
Questions?
嗯 谁能签加班报销?
Yeah, who signs the overtime slips?
不准加班 除非有上级批准
No OT, unless prior authorization.
大家可是新手上路 查一件没有头绪的案子 副队
A case goes from red to black by way of green, Lieutenant.
你们查到什么线索 需要加班的
You people bring me something that needs OT
会给你们加班费 在这之前
You'll get OT. until then,
就拿你们的薪水过日子吧
Live on your fucking salaries.
"你们父亲的事我很遗憾"
"I'm very sorry for your father.
"如果我能阻止 我会的"
"If I could've stopped it, I would have."
拿这个有什么用?
What can you do with this?
法庭上不能用
Nothing legally.
他没有牵涉进自己
He doesn't put himself in,
或是把任何人牵涉进去
Or anyone else for that matter.
看着这封信...
You can't read that letter...
你只能把那男人的被害 和他是目击证人联系到一起
And think that man was killed for any other reason than he was a witness.
既然和你无关 你道歉什么呢
Why apologize at all if you got nothing to do with it?
瞧
Look
我们失去了一位公诉方证人
We lost a state's witness.
就算是在Baltimore  那也算件不小的事了吧
Even in Baltimore, that's supposed to mean something, right?
就去找副局吧 给他看看
Just go to the deputy, show him what's what...
然后联系些实际的东西
And let's put something real together.
这案子需要能提供情报的
This case needs informants.
需要长期监视
It needs long-term surveillance.
最终会需要T3法案许可的窃听装置
And eventually, it's gonna need a Title 3 wiretap.
最重要的是 需要会用这些东西的警察
Most of all, it needs police who know how to work those things.
你觉得对外招摇我们的证人被枪杀了 对破案有好处?
You think it's good for business to put it out on the street that our witnesses get killed?
你以为外头还不知道?
You think it's not on the street already?
不要招摇 不要搞大
No grandstanding, no red balls.
就像我说的 我们速战速决
Like I said, we get in and out.
- June阿姨 - 嘿
- Aunt June. - Hey，sweety
嗯 希望你已经饿了
Yeah, I hope you're hungry.
饥肠辘辘
Starving.
嘿 Dee!
Hey, Dee!
你好吗 宝贝?
What's up, baby?
- 那是你舅舅? - 是的
- That your uncle? - Yeah.
我以为他长成别的样子
I thought he'd look different.
我的好兄弟 Dee
My man, Dee.
- 你好吗 伙计 - 你好吗
- What's up, man? - Hey,what's up
这就是小家伙?
This the little man?
嘿 看看你外甥的迷你版
Yo, you see how shorty favor your nephew here?
你好吗 小家伙
What's up, little man?
谁能拒绝这个小孩子呢
You ain't gonna be able to deny that child.
你想要我抱抱吗?
You wanna come to me?
我知道你想让我来抱抱
I know you tryin' to come to me.
刚在一直在小睡
Been napping.
- 是吗? - 刚醒
- Yeah? - Just woke up.
你抓着什么 让我看看你抓着什么
You got a grip, let me see your grip.
来吧 转个圈 给我们看看
C'mon, give us a twirl, let's take a look.
你要看什么呀
What you looking at?
- 给她端一盆热菜 - 好的
- Go fix her a hot plate. - All right.
什么都来点 她是这里最苗条的一个
Put everything on it. She's the skinniest thing in here.
来吧 姑娘 我们来招待你
Come on, girl, we gonna hook you up.
别被她耍了 她可能吃了
Don't let that fool you, she can eat, man.
你们怎么样 还好吧?
How y'all doing? You doing good?
嗯 嗯 都挺好的
Yeah, we all right.
她希望我搬进去 我正在考虑
She want me to move in, I'm thinking about it.
我们走走
Let's walk.
来 能帮我照顾一下小家伙吗
Here you come. You gonna take my man from me?
好的
Yeah.
照顾好我的小士兵
Be careful with my little soldier.
那个家伙有名字吗?
Got a name for that one?
没有
No.
但他是他们派在楼梯井的一个
But he's one of the boys they use in the stairwell.
他呢?
What about him?
那是"小东西"
That's Little Man.
他是打手
He's muscle.
你知道他的真名吗?
You know his real name?
线人?
Cl?
是的
Yeah.
你们需要一点私人空间吗?
You need some privacy?
不 没事
No, it's all right.
他不介意
He's cool.
帽子是怎么回事
What's with the hat?
和他说说 Bubbles
Go ahead, tell him, Bubbles.
我去那儿用我卖的帽子打掩护
I go down the way with some hats that I'm selling.
如果有谁是需要你们认识的 我就把红帽子戴在他们头上
If someone is someone you need to know I put the red hat on them
Kima就把照片拍下来
And Kima here take the pictures.
如果是小喽啰 我就用别的颜色
If they in the mix, they get another color.
如果无关紧要 就不给
If they ain't shit, they don't get shit.
所有戴帽子的家伙都是Barksdale的手下?
Everyone in the hat's part of Barksdale's crew?
在Terrace
At the Terrace.
我们还没有进入平房区
We haven't hit the low-rises yet.
漂亮
That's sharp.
我喜欢
I like that.
Bubbles可以过目不忘
Bubbles does not forget a face.
虽然记不住名字 但是 你瞧  这些脸都在我脑子里
Ain't so good with names, but, you know, faces I keep in my head.
我曾常常带他去通缉科 让他看通缉名册
I used to take him down to Escape Unit, let him look through the warrant books.
他会在晚上打电话给我
He'd call me up that night,
告诉我去这个角落 那个街头
Telling me to go to this corner, that corner.
嗯 每个人头给25元
Yeah, paid $25 a pop.
- 好赚头 - 是啊
- That's good money. - Yeah.
那这个帽子戏法能拿多少?
How much does the hat routine pay?
不用
Nothing.
我们义务的
We free on this.
狗娘养的把我的兄弟打残了
Motherfuckers beat my boy down.
谁?
Who?
在平房的小杂种们
Little hoppers in the low-rises.
你的兄弟是谁?
Who's your boy?
我的朋友
I got a friend.
比我年轻的白人小伙
Younger white boy.
之前常常在街角混 非常菜
Used to come down to the corners, real green.
我正在指点他
I was schooling him, you know?
出了什么事?
What happened?
他们海扁了他
They stomped him.
你瞧见了?
You see it?
为了几个子就那么糟蹋一个人
Fuck a man like that up for a couple dollars, you know?
他还在大学医院里 鼻子里插着气管
He still at University, tubes all up in his nose.
半句话都憋不出来
Can't say but a fucking word or two.
但是你瞧 世道就是这样 不是吗?
But you know, that's how it goes, right?
你感觉如何 Bubbles?
How you feeling, Bubbles?
精力充沛
Restless.
嗯 看得出来
Yeah, I could tell.
什么话? 就算你花10块钱招个鸭子 他能陪你到天明吗?
What the fuck? Can you hook a nigger up with $10 then till tomorrow?
我是说 你只要来接我就好 Kima
I mean, you know, just to carry me, Kima.
Bubbles
Bubbles.
谢谢
Obliged.
接下来几天别靠近高层区
Stay out of the projects the next couple of days...
好好保重
Just to be safe.
姑娘总喜欢对我操心
Girl's always fretting over me.
- 换身衣服 Bubs - 好 好
- Change it up, Bubs. - Yeah, yeah.
去东区吧
Go Eastside.
好 好
Yeah, yeah.
20元?
$20?
你会宠坏了他
You gonna spoil him with that shit.
我欣赏这工作
I respect the work.
他们提到了你的名字 还有Stringer...Wee-Bey
They used your name, Stringer, Wee-Bey...
Savino... Peanut
Savino, Peanut....
他们知道很多名字 他们知道得不少
They knew a lot of names. They knew a lot.
但是你什么都没说?
But you didn't say nothing?
该死的 伙计 我什么都不知道
Shit, man, I don't know nothing.
那你写什么?
What was you writing then?
嘿 他们说起那个被杀死的家伙 和他的孩子们
Yo, they was talking about the man who got killed and his kids,
- 他们让我写的 - 他们和你有什么关系 Dee?
- they asked me to write. - What you got to do with them, Dee?
是的 我也是这么说的
Yeah, that's what I said.
他们开始嚷嚷那些孩子有多么惨
Then they cried about how the kids ain't doing so good.
我想 就算我说我很遗憾那家伙被杀了 也没什么大不了的
I'm like, it ain't gonna hurt for me to say I'm sorry the man got killed.
你它妈干嘛说你很遗憾
Why the fuck you gotta say you're sorry?
混蛋们是想给你下套子
Motherfuckers tried to put your ass in the stir.
是的 但是结果不是的
Yeah, but it didn't turn out that way.
你瞧 我说的是 这是件丢脸的事...
You know, that's what I'm saying, it's a shame that y'all....
我是说
I'm saying,
那人身上发生的事很令人惋惜 对吧
It's a shame what happened to that man, all right?
因为他不过是从电梯里出来
'Cause he didn't do anything but come off the elevator
撞上了我在做的事情
When I was doing that thing that I was doing.
你在想什么 小子?
What you think, cuz?
关于什么?
About what?
我是说 那男人的事你是怎么想的?
I'm saying, what you think about what happened to the man?
你觉得是我们杀了那狗娘养的?
You think we killed the motherfucker?
想什么就说什么
Speak your mind.
伙计 我不知道
Man, I don't know.
没错
Exactly.
你不知道 你也不需要知道
You don't know, and you don't need to know.
如果我们做了 我们有理由 如果我们没有 我们也有理由
And if we did, we had a reason. And if we didn't, we had a reason.
不管怎样 这都和你没关系
But either way, you ain't got shit to do with it.
那不算在你头上 小老弟
It ain't on you, cuz.
你明白吗 这不算在你头上
You feel me? It ain't on you.
现在 要是你再被抓进去了
Now, if you get jacked again
我不想在听到你给谁写了什么狗屁玩意儿
I don't want to hear shit about you writing nothing to no one.
懂了吗?
Got it?
嗯
Yeah.
来吧 我们去乐一乐
Come on, let's have some good times
去啃些排骨 在他们吃光之前
And get some ribs before they done ate all the ribs up.
- 这案子没戏 Carv - 我知道
- This case isn't shit, Carv. - I know it.
我们围着这个狗娘养的转悠
We're dancing around with this motherfucker,
打狗屁报告...
Typing shit out...
给些戴帽子的杂种拍照
Taking pictures of assholes in hats.
- 搞什么狗屁啊 - 狗屁
- What the fuck is that? - It's bullshit.
我说我们现在马上过去 它妈的现在就去
I say we go down there right now. Right fucking now.
我们走进那些楼里 让他们见识见识
We go into those towers, and we let them know.
我是说真的
I'm serious.
你得让那些狗杂种知道你是什么来头
You got to let these motherfuckers know who you are.
你来吗?
You coming?
我跟你去
I'm with you.
Carv?
管它呢
What the hell?
那走吧
Let's do it.
来啊
Come on.
收摊
Shut it down.
50 50 快撤!
Five-O, five-O, break out.
嘿 过来 伙计 你这是要去哪儿啊
Yo, come here, man. Come here, where you going?
别搞得你不认识我似的 把手举起来
Don't act like you don't know me. Get your hands up.
- 放下它 - 扔下它们
- Put that down. - Drop that
- 扔了那玩意儿! 它妈的趴到地上! - 把手都举起来
- Drop that shit! Kiss the fucking ground! - Put your hands up.
别这么看着我  搞得我像在说什么鸟语似的 混蛋
Don't look at me like I ain't talking English mother fucker
你身上有针筒吗
You got a needle on you?
有什么东西能扎我吗?
Got anything in here that's gonna stick me?
没有?
No?
那是什么?
What's that?
你口袋里有什么?
What you got in your pockets?
你瞧 把裤子脱下来
You know what? Put your pants down, man.
脱掉你的裤子 趴倒地上
Put your pants down and get down on the ground.
它妈的趴到地上!
Get down on the fucking ground!
好了 两腿分开
All right, spread your shit out.
- 鞋子不错 - 想点愉快的
- Nice shoes. - Think a happy thought.
你们干嘛不去别的地方撒野?
Why don't you go somewhere else with that bullshit?
不务正业的杂种
No-good motherfuckers.
趴着 伙计 趴好了 趴好了
Stay down, man, stay down. stay down.
你们都可以去跟Barksdale那伙人说 这些楼是我们的
Y'all can let Barksdale and them know who owns these towers.
因为我们回来了
'Cause we're coming back.
- 我已经忍无可忍了 - 亲我屁股啊!
- I'm sick of this shit. - Kiss my ass!
我们先闪 一小时后回来 把每个人都抓个现行
We roll out, come back in an hour, catch everybody dirty.
- 让你见识一下怎么回事 - 都是扯淡 伙计
- You'll see how that goes. - That's bullshit, man.
- 嘿 趴好了 伙计 - 搞什么啊
- Yo, stay down, man. - That's fucked up.
什么都没做啊
Man ain't did nothing.
想要什么吗?
Want something?
滚 傻蛋
Move, shitbird.
我什么都没做
I ain't doing nothing.
是吗? 我没什么可给你的
Really? I got nothing for you.
我的眼睛 我的眼睛
My eye, my eye.
看你还能给谁抛媚眼
Who you gonna eyefuck now?
你是来真的吗? 你敢把血弄到我车上?
Are you serious? You bleed on my car?
别把血弄到我车上  它妈的给我从车上下来
Don't bleed on my car. Get your shit off my car.
你它妈的什么毛病?
What the fuck's the matter with you?
看得见吗?
Got a visual?
操
Fuck.
去呼叫电台
Get the radio.
11:35
11:35,
信号13!(请求支援)
Signal 13.
Franklin771号 外院
771 Franklin,in the Court.
狗娘养的!
Son of a bitch!
发生交火 发生交火 警员需要支援
Shots fired, shots fired. Officers need assistance.
我受到攻击 信号13!
I'm hit! Signal 13.
警员负伤 警员负伤!
Officer down, Officer down!
警员负伤
Officer down
该死的!
Shit!
喂
Hello?
- 看过报纸了吗? - 什么?
- You seen the paper? - What?
新闻报纸 去拿
The newspaper, get it.
嘿 孩子们
Hey, kids.
啊 不
Oh, no.
谋杀案涉嫌毒品犯罪
证人遇刺身亡
你开心了 婊子?
You happy now, bitch?
McNulty!
妈的他在哪儿?
Where in fuck is he?
厄 他去专案组了 警长 去缉毒科了...
He's detailed, Major, to Narcotics--
我它妈的知道他去专案组了 它妈的我已经知道了!
I fucking know where he's detailed. I fucking already know that!
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
他现在在哪儿?
Where is he right now?
我可以呼他 长官
I can page him, sir.
把这张该死的桌子从我组里搬走
Move that fucking desk out of my unit.
我不要这狗娘养的桌子在我组里
I do not want that fucking man's desk in my unit.
那是Crutchfield的桌子
That's Crutchfield's desk.
Crutchfield的?
Crutchfield's?
McNulty坐在这里
McNulty sits here.
它妈的什么事啊?
What the fuck was that about?
你看今天的报纸了没?
Did you see today's paper?
只看了体育版
Just sports.
你得去看看头版
You gotta check out the front page.
你觉得他们会怎么收拾他?
What do you think they'll do to him?
让我来告诉你些事
Let me tell you something.
就算他被捉奸 和副局的老婆搞在一起
If he gets caught with his dick up the ass of the deputy's wife...
也没比被发现他是这件事的 始作俑者的结果厉害
He's still gonna have more of a career than if they find out he's behind that story.
副队
Lieutenant.
我看到了新闻报道  我想告诉你 我跟这事没关系
I saw the story in the paper. I want you to know I had nothing to do.
他们突袭我们 老板
They jumped us, Boss.
谁?
Who?
那些楼里的黑佬
Fucking project niggers.
你们在凌晨两点到这里来干什么?
What are you doing here at 2:00 in the morning?
实地调查 长官 份内事
Field interviews, sir, police work.
份内事?
Police work?
是的
Yeah.
我这有个14岁的小孩卧院  伤势严重 但还算稳定
I got a 14-year-old in critical but stable condition at University...
两个目击者说你们其中之一
And two witnesses who say one of you princes
狠狠地用枪把砸了他
Cold-cocked him with the butt-end of a pistol.
没有 长官
No, sir.
他母亲告到了内务部  递交了一份正式的野蛮执法的指控
I got his mother over at lID. filing a formal brutality charge...
对Herc来说 已经是两年来第四次了
Which for Herc will make an even four in the last two years.
- 没有一个成立的 - 但都是真的
- None sustained. - But all of them true.
我们以为...
We thought that--
你们昨晚让我损失了一辆皇冠(警车)
I got one less Crown Vic than I had last night.
两件防弹背心在车里被焚烧
I'm out two Kevlar vests that burned in the car...
两个手持对讲机 一把短枪
Two hand-held radios, a shotgun...
然后在未来的一到两个星期里 我还要失去养伤的这个笨蛋
And I'm about to lose this idiot here for a week or two of medical.
换来什么呢?
And for what?
副队 我们以为...
Lieutenant, we thought
你们从这次凌晨亮点来Terrace
What did you all learn when you went to the Terrace
做实地调查 到底了解到了什么?
At 2:00 in the morning to conduct field interviews?
付出了这个代价之后 我们到底得到了什么有用的情报
What valuable information did we acquire from this situation?
内务部在下午之前 会对你们三个一一调查...
IID is gonna be on all three of you by afternoon...
如果在那之前  你们不能编一个像样的说法出来
And if you don't get a story straight by then..
你们会得到一份厚厚的报告  离上法庭也就不远了
You're gonna have a file thick enough to see the light of a trial board.
现在告诉我
Now tell me,
谁对那小子下手的?
Who cold-cocked the kid?
我
Me.
为什么?
Why?
他惹毛了我
He pissed me off.
不 Pryzbylewski警员 他没有惹毛你
No, Officer Pryzbylewski, he did not piss you off.
他让你担心你和你同伴的安危
He made you fear for your safety and that of your fellow officers.
我现在猜测 也许...
I'm guessing now, but maybe...
你看到他捡起瓶子 要威胁Hauk和Carver警员
He was seen to pick up a bottle and menace officers Hauk and Carver...
而他们已经被楼上飞落的杂物击伤
Both of whom had already sustained injury from flying projectiles.
在那种情况下 你没有使用致命武器
Rather than use deadly force in such a situation...
而是决定靠近那个年轻人
Maybe you elected to approach the youth,
命令他放下瓶子
Ordering him to drop the bottle.
也许他举起了瓶子继续示威
Maybe when he raised the bottle in a threatening manner...
你用了手电筒
You used a Kel-Light,
而不是你警枪的枪把
Not the handle of your service weapon...
去阻止了嫌疑人
To incapacitate the suspect.
好好练练
Go practice.
要是你对调查人员乱说一气
You fuck the bullshit up when you talk to lnternal...
我可救不了你 你得靠你自己了
I can't fix it, you're on your own.
把传讯推迟到三点
Push the arraignments back to 3:00.
那Gillette案呢?
And the Gillette case?
Gillette案打回去重定时间
The Gillette trial goes back on the move docket.
快 跟我一起走 我迟到了
Come on, walk with me. I'm running late.
不是我
It wasn't me.
新闻里引用了你的话
The story quoted you.
狗娘养的记者 他打电话采访我的时候 已经核实了这件事
Reporter has the story confirmed when he calls me about the quote.
我还能说什么?
What am I gonna say?
不 他不是证人? 不 他上星期没有到我的法庭上作证?
No, he wasn't a witness? No, he didn't testify in my court last week?
什么?
What?
你觉得这事还没有议论纷纷?
You don't think it's around about the witness?
律师 职员 陪审团 大家都在议论
Lawyers, clerks, jurors, everybody talks.
我是众矢之的 法官大人
I'm in the shit here, Your Honor.
我能对你说什么呢
What can I tell you?
我打电话找了副局长 不是报纸 我得走了
I called the deputy, not the newspapers. I gotta run.
你该对他们停职
You should have hung them.
如果我让他们停职 我就停了自己的职
If I hang them, I hang myself.
我是负责的人 记得吗?
I'm the man in charge, remember?
何况 你不会把自己的人交给内务部
Besides, you don't give your people up to IID.
你不能那么做
You don't do that.
就算他们害得一个14岁小孩 进了重症监护室?
Even if they put a 14-year-old kid into Critical Care?
这案子 它...
This case, it's just....
那就脱身好了
Get out of it.
- 我要怎么脱身呢? - 我不知道
- How do I do that? - I don't know.
不过只要你不玩 也就不会输
But you can't lose if you don't play.
我一直听到的是 如果你不玩 也就赢不了
I always heard it that you can't win if you don't play.
局里把一件他们不想办的案子压在你身上
The department puts you on a case it doesn't want.
给你派的人都是没用的 不值得信任的
You're given people that are useless or untrustworthy.
没错
Correct.
要是你查得紧 要是惹到了谁
If you push too hard, and any shit hits the fan...
到头来都是怪到你头上
You'll be blamed for it.
没错
Correct.
要是你查得松 抓不到人  你还是会背黑锅
If you don't push hard enough, and there's no arrest, you'll be blamed for that, too.
没错
Correct.
游戏被操纵了
The game is rigged.
但是要是你不玩 你就不会输了
But you cannot lose if you do not play.
嘿!
Hey!
嘿 你这混蛋!
Hey, you fuckheads!
嘿 我是警察!
Hey, police!
- 喂 是的 - Daniels上尉?
- Hello. yeah. - Lieutenant Daniels?
是谁?
Who was that?
是大学医院的值班警察
It was the duty officer down at University hospital.
出什么事了?
What happened?
他的一只眼睛瞎了
He's blind in one eye.
谁?
Who?
那孩子
The kid.
那个14岁的孩子
The 14-year-old.